{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Take your stinking paws off me, you damned dirty ape.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?\"","\"Toga! Toga!\"","\"Attica! Attica!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Planet of the Apes'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jason Bateman","incorrectAnswers":["Javier Bardem","Colin Firth","Tim Roth"],"question":"Which actor has acted in both Arrested Development and DodgeBall: A True Underdog Story?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory","incorrectAnswers":["The Sweet Factory","The Chocolatier's Gamble","The Candy Kingdom"],"question":"Which book contains the character Willy Wonka?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1947","incorrectAnswers":["1953","1959","1941"],"question":"In What Year Did India Gain Independence From The United Kingdom?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Makin' It","incorrectAnswers":["Cum on Feel the Noize","Barbie Girl","Don't Leave Me This Way"],"question":"David Naughton had a one hit wonder with which song?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"A beanball","incorrectAnswers":["A curveball","A fastball","A slider"],"question":"What is the baseball term for when a pitcher intentionally hits a batter with the pitch?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Primitivism","incorrectAnswers":["Baroque","Renaissance","Neoclassicism"],"question":"The painting \"The Sleeping Gypsy\" by Henri Rousseau is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Japan","North Korea","Mongolia"],"question":"Beijing is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rammstein","incorrectAnswers":["Cascada","Blue System","Scorpions"],"question":"Which German industrial metal band released the studio album 'Mutter'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Madonna","Mika"],"question":"Which musician released the album 'Low'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Nicole Kidman","incorrectAnswers":["Scarlett Johansson","Reese Witherspoon","Natalie Portman"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Satine in \"Moulin Rouge!\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"White","incorrectAnswers":["Maroon","Red","Blue"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Ireland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the album 'Made in Heaven'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Megadeath","incorrectAnswers":["Metallica","Slayer","Sodom"],"question":"Name The Thrash Metal Band Headed By Guitarist Dave Mustaine","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Caravan","incorrectAnswers":["Curtain","Commissary ","Cartel"],"question":"What is the term for a convoy of vehicles or merchants traveling together?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","Metallica","Nirvana"],"question":"Which band had Ringo Starr as its drummer?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"bounced","incorrectAnswers":["delayed","rejected","invalid"],"question":"What is the expression used to describe a check that failed to clear due to insufficient funds?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Wimbledon","incorrectAnswers":["The US PGA","The Presidents Cup","Le Mans 24 Hours"],"question":"Which of these is a competition in Tennis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nevadan","incorrectAnswers":["Nevadite","Nevadien","Nevadanian"],"question":"What is the more common term for a person from Nevada?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Parkin ","incorrectAnswers":["Eccles","Simnal","Madeira"],"question":"Which cake is traditionally eaten on 5th November in the United Kingdom to commemorate Guy Fawkes night?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Warrior","incorrectAnswers":["No Country for Old Men","The Terminator","Lawrence of Arabia"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'The son of a former boxer is trained by his father for a mixed martial arts tournament.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Moonlight","incorrectAnswers":["Arrival","Fences","Hacksaw Ridge"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2016?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Beyonce","Adele","Lady Gaga"],"question":"Who found a hit with Calvin Harris with the song 'We Found Love'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A scientist in want of a companion creates a living creature, who turns out to be misunderstood and is subject to torment by all he meets","incorrectAnswers":["A tiger visits a house for tea and eats everything it has inside","A boy makes friends with a Jewish boy at a concentration camp ","A brief history of space, science and time "],"question":"Which of these is the plot to the novel Frankenstein by Mary Shelley?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Norway","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia","Latvia","Lithuania"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Finland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Jerusalem","incorrectAnswers":["Tel Aviv","Tripoli","Damascus"],"question":"What is the capital city of Israel?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Czech Republic","incorrectAnswers":["Australia","Hungary","Turkey"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Prague?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kampala","incorrectAnswers":["Nuku'alofa","Yamoussoukro","Lilongwe"],"question":"What is the capital city of Uganda?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Saudi Arabia","incorrectAnswers":["Djibouti","Somalia","Eritrea"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Yemen?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"1914","incorrectAnswers":["1922","1937","1946"],"question":"On which Christmas day did English and German troops play football?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ash Tree","incorrectAnswers":["Oak Tree","Fir Tree","Apple Tree"],"question":"Which of these trees has winged seeds?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lansing","incorrectAnswers":["Ann Arbor","Flint","Grand Rapids"],"question":"What is the state capital of Michigan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Voyages Extraordinaires","Percy Jackson & the Olympians","Twilight"],"question":"In which book series does 'Neville Longbottom' appear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Borborygmus","incorrectAnswers":["Taradiddle","Ill-willie","Quomodocunquizing"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a rumbling or gurgling noise in the intestines'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Aurora","incorrectAnswers":["Rapunzel","Belle","Cinderella"],"question":"What is the name of the beautiful princess in Sleeping Beauty?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bull","incorrectAnswers":["A Cock","A Rooster","A Buck"],"question":"A male alligator is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Peter Dinklage","incorrectAnswers":["J.K. Simmons","Paul Rudd","Tom Hiddleston"],"question":"The role of Eitri in the Marvel Cinematic Universe is played by which actor?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Hugh Jackman","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Fassbender","Jim Carrey","Robert Redford"],"question":"Which actor has featured in both X-Men: Days of Future Past and Deadpool 2?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Daredevil","incorrectAnswers":["Spider-Man","Iron Man","Captain America"],"question":"Which Marvel superhero and lawyer has the enhanced senses of hearing and smell, allowing him to hear heartbeats from 20 feet away and track people by scent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A Lamb","incorrectAnswers":["A Puppy","A Fish","A Swan"],"question":"In the nursery rhyme, what animal belonged to a girl named Mary?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1988","incorrectAnswers":["1984","1992","1996"],"question":"In which year was Die Hard first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Tennyson","incorrectAnswers":["Keats","Shelley","Wordsworth"],"question":"Which later poet was heavily influenced by Lord Byron and wrote 'The Lord of Burleigh' in 1842?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Deltoid","incorrectAnswers":["Bicep","Tricep","Gluteal"],"question":"What is the name of the large muscle that covers the shoulder joint?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Quito","incorrectAnswers":["Lilongwe","Cairo","Santo Domingo"],"question":"What is the capital city of Ecuador?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Christian Bale","incorrectAnswers":["Keanu Reeves","Dan Aykroyd","Donald Sutherland"],"question":"Which actor played Batman in the Dark Knight trilogy?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"24","incorrectAnswers":["27","20","30"],"question":"How Old Was James Dean When He Died?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man","incorrectAnswers":["Little Women","David Copperfield","Jane Eyre"],"question":"In which book does 'Charles Stewart Parnell' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Wish You Were Here'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Seven","incorrectAnswers":["Fight Club","The Shawshank Redemption","Interview with the Vampire"],"question":"What was the name of the iconic '90s thriller starring Brad Pitt and Morgan Freeman?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Afroasiatic","Kra–Dai","Uralic"],"question":"The language 'Gujarati' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Potassium hydroxide","incorrectAnswers":["Silicon dioxide","Isopropyl alcohol","Deuterium Oxide"],"question":"What chemical has the formula KOH?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dynamite","incorrectAnswers":["Nuclear Fission","Gravity","Radio Waves"],"question":"The invention of what in 1867, made Alfred Nobel famous?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Depeche Mode","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Dead or Alive","Radiohead"],"question":"Which English band released the studio album 'Ultra'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Melbourne","incorrectAnswers":["Cape Town","Buenos Aires","Rio de Janeiro"],"question":"The first ever Olympic Games to be held south of the equator opened in which city in 1956?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cleveland Cavaliers","incorrectAnswers":["Cleveland Inter","Cleveland Bills","Cleveland Sounders"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Cleveland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Winston Churchill","incorrectAnswers":["Neville Chamberlain","Anthony Eden","Tony Blair"],"question":"Which British Prime Minister was in office for the majority of World War II?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"An Ice Skating Rink","incorrectAnswers":["A Football Pitch","A Tennis Court","A Rugby Pitch"],"question":"In the world of sport what has the maximum dimensions of 60 metres by 30 metres?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hamlet","incorrectAnswers":["King Lear","Julius Caesar","Othello"],"question":"In which Shakespearean tragedy Does Laertes appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Swahili","incorrectAnswers":["Yoruba","Hindi","Latin"],"question":"\"Hakuna Matata\" is a phrase from which language?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jane Eyre","incorrectAnswers":["The Lady of the Camellias","Little Women","David Copperfield"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'There was no possibility of taking a walk that day.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spanish","incorrectAnswers":["Italian","English","Bengali"],"question":"What language do the locals speak in Bogota?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Canada","incorrectAnswers":["United States of America","Mexico","Russia"],"question":"The world's biggest meteor crater is located in which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","incorrectAnswers":["Chile","Sweden","Uruguay"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1954 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Internal secretory glands","incorrectAnswers":["Bees","Fresh water environments","Japanese people"],"question":"What is Endocrinology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Michael Ende","incorrectAnswers":["Friedrich Engels","Erich Maria Remarque","Karl May"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Neverending Story'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1993","incorrectAnswers":["1981","1985","1989"],"question":"In which year was Jurassic Park released?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lye","incorrectAnswers":["Rye","Bye","Dye"],"question":"What is the name of the strong alkaline solution frequently used in soap making and drain cleaning?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Elton John","incorrectAnswers":["Paul McCartney","Paul Simon","Michael Jackson"],"question":"Who Wrote The Music To The 1994 Movie “The Lion King”","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1789","incorrectAnswers":["1890","1921","1712"],"question":"In What Year Was The French Declaration Of The Rights Of Man?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Peter Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed The Hobbit: The Desolation of Smaug?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Treaties of Paris","incorrectAnswers":["Treaties of Vienna","Treaties of London","Treaties of Berlin"],"question":"What treaties ended the Napoleonic wars?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A shadowy freedom fighter plots to overthrow the tyrannical government.","incorrectAnswers":["Two men searching for work in 1920s Mexico convince an old prospector to help them mine for gold.","A New York City mob boss transfers control of his empire to his reluctant son.","An Army officer serving in Vietnam is tasked with assassinating a renegade Special Forces Colonel."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie V for Vendetta?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Devil's Island","incorrectAnswers":["Alcatraz","Spike Island","Australia"],"question":"What infamous prison island was off the coast of French Guiana?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sauternes ","incorrectAnswers":["Riesling","Merlot","Malbec"],"question":"What Wine Is Traditionally Matched With Pate And Brioche?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Thucydides","incorrectAnswers":["Baruch Spinoza","Heraclitus","Ludwig Wittgenstein"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'History is Philosophy teaching by examples'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Japonic","incorrectAnswers":["Sino-Tibetan","Austroasiatic","Austronesian"],"question":"The language 'Japanese' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"San Francisco","incorrectAnswers":["Los Angeles","New York City","Chicago"],"question":"The \"Zebra murders\" of 1973-74 took place in which US city?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jennifer Lawrence","incorrectAnswers":["Catherine Deneuve","Audrey Hepburn","Rachel Weisz"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in films including X-Men: Days of Future Past and American Hustle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A Nightmare on Elm Street","incorrectAnswers":["Fast Times at Ridgemont High","Taxi Driver","Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Freddy Krueger'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Gamal Abdul Nasser","incorrectAnswers":["Ahmed Sabzi","Omar Sharif","Asser Yasin"],"question":"Who was the President of Egypt in 1956 who nationalized the Suez Canal, causing British and French troops to invade the region?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Killer Croc","incorrectAnswers":["Bad Baboon","Lethal Lemur ","Raging Rhino"],"question":"Which DC Comics supervillain is a menace to Batman?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Maine","incorrectAnswers":["Massachusetts","Vermont","Connecticut"],"question":"Which of the U.S. states borders only one other state?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"RAV4","incorrectAnswers":["3-Series","Silver Ghost","XK120"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Toyota?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Gloria","incorrectAnswers":["Higher Ground","Red Red Wine","Hallelujah"],"question":"Which song was originally recorded by Them and was later covered by Patti Smith?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The World's Local Bank","incorrectAnswers":["There are some things money can't buy","Everywhere you want to be","Because Change Happens"],"question":"What is the marketing slogan of HSBC?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Uganda","incorrectAnswers":["Niger","Colombia","The Czech Republic"],"question":"Which country is associated with the drink waragi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bhutan","incorrectAnswers":["Azerbaijan","Mozambique","Taiwan"],"question":"Thimphu is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Organic particles","incorrectAnswers":["Existence","Ticks and mites","Sleep"],"question":"What is Aerobiology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Nicki Minaj","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American singer and songwriter released the song 'Like a Virgin'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Black Russian","incorrectAnswers":["Stinger","Harvey Wallbanger","Manhattan"],"question":"What cocktail is made from vodka and Kahlua?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Crosshairs","incorrectAnswers":["Target","Aiming point","Scope lines"],"question":"What is the technical name for the pair of intersecting lines in a firearm scope?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Vladimir Putin","incorrectAnswers":["Boris Yeltsin","Dmitry Medvedev","Mikhail Gorbachev"],"question":"Who became president of Russia in 2012?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Moses","incorrectAnswers":["Goliath","King Herod","Jesus"],"question":"In the bible, who says, \"I will now turn aside, and see this great sight, why the bush is not burnt\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"May the odds ever be in your favor.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"After all, tomorrow is another day!\"","\"I'll have what she's having.\"","\"Exercise gives you endorphins. Endorphins make you happy. Happy people just don’t shoot their husbands. They just don’t.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Hunger Games'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Matrix","incorrectAnswers":["Pulp Fiction","Forrest Gump","Joker"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A hacker discovers the life he knows is the elaborate deception of an evil cyber-intelligence.'","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Istanbul","incorrectAnswers":["Tehran","Dubai","Manama"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Turkey?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"South America","incorrectAnswers":["Africa","India","The Middle East"],"question":"From which part of the world do pineapples originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Inspector Clouseau","incorrectAnswers":["Austin Powers","Dr. Evil","Borat"],"question":"Which character, played by Peter Sellers, famously mispronounces words like 'room', 'phone', and 'monkey'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Black","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","One","Eight"],"question":"In Spanish, what is the meaning of the word 'negro'?","difficulty":"medium"},